Guide to the Sam Shepard Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Films, 1982-1998
  This series is divided into two subseries. The first, films for which Shepard wrote the screenplay, includes: notes, annotated drafts, dialogue rewrites, publicity, correspondence, contracts, music notes, production notes and schedules. Of the films in this subseries, Silent Tongue includes the most information (1 linear foot), followed by Far North(.25 linear feet.), Onibaba(.25 linear feet), Paris, TX(4 folders), and Plain Fate, an unfinished work (1 folder). The second subseries of films is for those which Shepard did not write the screenplay but in which he appears as an actor, Bright Angel(1989-90) and Voyager(1990-91) both include screenplay typescripts with Shepard's annotations. Thunderheart(1991) includes storyboards and color photographs, Dash and Lily(1998)includes an advertisement.
  - Films written by Shepard, 1982-1992
    - Paris, TX (1984)
      - Notes: dialog re-writes, editing notes,10 pages, March 22, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence from Peter Kaminsky and Wim Wenders, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Advertising sample (5.5 x 8.5 color card) (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Reviews, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Far North (1988)
      - Notes regarding make-up, hospital scene, and synopsis, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Notes on second draft regarding budget, music and sound, 10 pages, February 1987 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Notes on cutting/editing, 8 pages, January 1988 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Vehicle card, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Advertisements, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Reviews, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Black and white publicity photograph of Sam Shepard on set (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, includes: program for Minnesota film premiere and program and materials from 1988 Telluride Film Festival, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Audiocassette of New York City-New Orleans music sessions, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - VHS Videocassette of film transfer with visual time code, second cut, January 28, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - VHS Videocassette of film transfer with visual time code, transfer number four, March 4, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Plain Fate (unfinished, February, 1988)
      - Signed annotated typescript (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Onibaba (1991)
      - Handwritten notes and partial draft in blue spiral notebook, 18 pages May 1992 Notebook also contains notes, sketches, and dialogue for play, "States of Shock", 1991; screenplay, "The Homesman," May 1991; and play "original deception," May 1991, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - First draft outline, annotated typescript, July 11, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Clippings regarding 1965 Japanese film Onibaba directed by Kaneto Shindo (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Contract with Toho International for film rights purchased by Shepard, September 21, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Silent Tongue (1992)
      - First draft May 1988, Virginia and August 1988 Natchidoches, La. (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Contact sheet for Red Clay Ramblers, March 19, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Location notes, memos, and map, October 24, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Third revision, slightly annotated in blue, black and red ink, January 1992 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Third revision typescript annotated in red ink (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Third revision typescript lightly annotated in black ink and blue highlighter, January 1992 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Third revision lightly annotated in red and black ink and minimal blue highlighter, January 1992 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Notebook with headings of outline, personnel, and notes, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Shooting script, March 5,1992 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Editing, continuity, location, and extras notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Music notes, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Audiocassette of medicine show music, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Two audiocassettes of Dino's music, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Possible prologue photos (photocopies from published sources), undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Notes on cuts, August 1993 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Notes on final trims of opening from editor Bill Yahraus, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Vehicle card, "Now Filming" (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Folder containing: crew resumes, production telephone messages, information about stuntmen, casting suggestions for "Reeves," production schedule, and storyboard drawings by Michael Peal, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Photographs from set: 8x10 black and white of Alan Bates, Dermot Mulroney, and a female in front of stagewagon and 3x5 of burial tree (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Synopsis for press kit draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Clippings and reviews, 1992-1994 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Film guide from Sundance Film Festival featuring Silent Tongue, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Poster (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence including: ICM correspondence regarding contract for film,1991; Grey Larsen regarding music for film, 1988, and article written for Esquire magazine about film, 1988, 1991, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - A Rage of Unknown Origin, undated
      - Notes, two typescript pages, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Films in which Shepard performed, 1989-1998
    - Bright Angel, screenplay by Richard Ford (1989-1990)
      - Screenplay typescript by Richard Ford, second draft with Shepard's annotations, August, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Screenplay typescript by Ford, latest draft, with Shepard's annotations, August, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Color transparency advertising film, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Voyager (1991)
      - Annotated photocopy of book titled Homo Faberby Max Frisch, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Annotated article on Max Frisch, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Screenplay typescript third draft with Shepard's annotations, February 1990 - March 1990 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Film contract, January 1990 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Location stills by Volker, color photographs in blue notebook, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Production schedules, maps, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Photographs on set of Shepard and Julie Delpy by Bridgette LaCombe, includes 16 black and white faxes and 19 color copies, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 11-12)
      - Production notes by Castle Hill Productions including cast, credits and synopsis, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Booklet containing synopsis, photographs, artistic and technical participants in film (in French), undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence with Volker, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Thunderheart (1991)
      - Storyboards for scenes 38, 40, 70, 119-122, and 131-133 (photocopies) (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Two color photographs, taped together, unidentified, but presumed to be taken on the set of Thunderheart, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Dash and Lilly (1998)
      - Advertisement in Variety magazine, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
- Literary Criticism, 1984
  This series is comprised of a review by Shepard of Peter Handke's novel The Weight of the World, including a letter from Handke's editor, Shepard's draft, and a copy of the essay as published in Vanity Fair, September 1984.
  - Review by Shepard of Peter Handke's novel The Weight of the World, including letter from Handke's editor, Shepard's draft and a copy of the essay published in Vanity Fair, September 1984 (Box 18, Folder 20)
- Notebooks, 1981-1995
  The Notebooks series includes handwritten notes, dialogue ideas, small drawings, and journal entries, usually in spiral bound notebooks. Some entries are personal and many were or were intended to be developed into longer works.
  - Various subjects including: Synthetic Tears screenplay outline, Transfixion New Mexico, Fool for Love notes, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Blue spiral containing notes on various subjects (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    "Dream in Borad Day," prose fragment, July, 23, 1982; "script fragment beginning," Int. Lee and Old Man," August 8, 1982; "P.O.V's prose, fragment," undated; "After all I'd been through with this guy," prose fragment, October 11, 1982; "The Flood has occurred and he could not be bothered to save himself from drowning..." prose fragment, undated; "Second Chance" undated
  - Various subjects on loose sheets, 1984, 1987-1989, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    "Machine Dreams: "Film Synopsis," December 25, 1984
    "Denial," film sketch, February 1984
    "History of the Dog," undated
    Film sketch beginning, "A Man has a dream about a murder..." undated
    "Jealousy is not a pretty thing," October 23, 1988
    "States" notes, February, 1989
    "1957" film notes, January 1, 1987
    "The Man Who Could Not Stop Crying," October 3, 1988
  - Various subjects bound in black leather book with red marbled endpapers, 1989-1990, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    "Thin Skin – What Any Woman Can Do To You," 1989
    "J.D.'s Collapse," December 1998
    "Southwest Chief – L.A. to Chicago," February 1989
    "More Urgent Emergencies," April, 1989
    "Wild to the Wild," May, 1989
    "Ancient Fear of the Fiddle," May, 1989
    "Open Suitcase," January, 1990
  - Various subjects, 1992-1993, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    quotes dated August, 1992
    "Separation: Horrors of the Road," September 1992
    "Simms – Tall Stories Solid 7," September, 1993
    "One Last Favor," playscript September, 1992
    "No Better Place than the Present," undated
  - Various subjects in black spiral-bound notebook, 1993-1996 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    "Brecht Clown Play - Joe - World Was Green - At theEdge of the World," November 1993
    "Confession - Obsession - Blessing or Curse," "Oedipus," October 1995
    "Great Place," November 1995
    "Sins of the Distant Past," "Marfa Lights," February 1996; November 1993-January 1996,(black cover)
  - Various subjects, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    "Turkey Sag," January, 1994 "Gary Cooper ofthe Landscape," January, 1994 "A Weakness for Horses," January, 1994 Actors, Simpatico, "An Actors Doubt," January, 1994
    poem "My mother loved the sea..." March, 1994
    "Dreaming of a way to Enter the Unbearable Present," April, 1994
    "Self Made Man (Divine Providence," undated
    "Questions for Junior Brown," March, 1995
    "Once," May, 1995
    "Dignity," May, 1995
    "A Man's Man," May, 1995
    "Reading-Oct. 6 -"Y"," April 24, 1994
    "Volador; Mundo Nuevo," July, 1994
    "Place," May, 1995
  - Various subjects on three loose pages: Angel, White Horse on Hudson, God, Tuna, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1982-1998
  Topics include the publication of Shepard's works in magazines and journals as excerpts, as well as in their entirety; correspondence with agent Lois Berman. Aside from general correspondence, this series also includes correspondence from Joseph Chaikin and Barry Daniels and correspondence from Shepard's son, Jesse, as noted [Restricted]. For Shepard's 40-year correspondence with Johnny Dark, see the Southwestern Writers Collection 106, The Sam Shepard and Johnny Dark Collection.
  - 1982 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Lawson, Wayne, November 10, 1982
  - 1983 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Phillips, Jerrold, March 2, 1983
    Berman, Lois, August 18, 1983
    Cuyama Valley Exchange Club. August 29, 1983
    Mitchell, Joni, circa 1983
  - 1984 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Rogers, S[Sam], April 13, 1984
    Gantcher, Neal(to Martin Licker), June 6, 1984
    Kirwin, Lynne (to Lois Berman), June 27, 1984
    Allen, Lewis (to Lois Berman), June 29, 1984
    Shewey, Don (to Lois Berman), July 12, 1984
    Shewey, Don, July 12, 1984
    Berman, Lois, July 17, 1984
    Allen, Lewis, July 17, 1984
    McCrum, Robert (to Lois Berman), August 23, 1984
    * restricted Shepard, Jesse, October 9, 1984
    Lynn and Jack (first names only), November 26, 1984
  - 1985 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    * restricted Shepard, Jesse, February 20, 1985
    Ward, Melinda, February 28, 1985
    Weiler, Robert S., June 28, 1985
    Allen, Lewis, July 3, 1985
    Sato, Suzanne, July 8, 1985
  - 1986 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    * restricted Shepard, Jesse, February 2, 1986
    Gotlieb, Howard, April 4, 1986. (Includes Boston University's Shepard collection listing.)
  - 1988 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    Klein, Don, April 25, 1988
    Mark, Steven (to Martin Licker), June 7, 1988
    Wenders, Wim, July 22, 1988
    Crane, Joan, July 28, 1988
    Crane, Joan, August 2, 1988
    Wexler, Haskell, September 30, 1988
    Wexler, Haskell, October 21, 1988
    "Mom," November 2, 1988
    Bryer, Jackson, November 30, 1988
    Daugherty, Pat, December 19, 1988
  - 1989 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    Daniels, Barry, January 5, 1989
    Berman, Lois, May 17, 1989. Includes "American Dreams" programs
    Ford, Richard, August 10, 1989
    Sinise, Gary, November 4, 1989
  - 1990 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    Jewell, Cathy, October 18, 1990
    Halpern, Daniel, October 25,1990
    Jewell, Cathy, October 25, 1990
    Hill, Steve, December 18, 1990
  - 1991 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Jewell, Cathy, January 14, 1991
    Berman, Lois, January 17, 1991
    Newman, Paul, May 15, 1991
    Eberle, Martin, June 28, 1991, Includes six 9 1/2 x 11 1/2 black and white photographs of Shepard and others
  - 1992 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    "R.J."(initials only), October 8, 1992
    Callens, Johan (to Lois Berman), October 30, 1992
  - 1993 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    Callens, Johan (to Lois Berman), October 1, 1993
    Kulkhe, K., October 6, 1993
  - 1994 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    Shelley, Guy, March 15, 1994
    Boals, Judy, April 15, 1994. Includes poster and slides from a Paris production of Icarus's Mother.
  - 1995 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    Boals, Judy, March 24, 1995. Includes Theater Hall of Fame program
  - 1996 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    O'Hearn, Patrick, March 12, 1996
    West, Robert, Jr., March 17, 1996
    Jones, O-Lan, March 21, 1996
    Boals, Judy, April 19, 1996
    Boals, Judy, April 22, 1996
    Kirchwey, Karl, April 22, 1996
    Morris, Tom (to Judy Boals), April 24, 1996
    Houghton, James, April,25, 1996
    McKimmie, Ilyse, May 1, 1996
    West, Robert Jr., May 1, 1996
    Boals, Judy, May 2, 1996
    Oliver, Liz, May 2, 1996
    Teale, Sarah, May 3, 1996
    "New Yorker" editorial office, May 18, 1996
    Giuliani, Rudolph, May 22, 1996. re: 50th anniversary of Tony Awards
    Butcher, Peggy (to Judy Boals), May 23, 1996
    Stevenson, Isabelle (June 6, 1996)
    McCormick, Anne (to Luann Walther), June 10, 1996
    Allen, Georgina, June 11, 1996. Includes cover art for Methuen publications of Plays 1 and 3.
    Pacquette, Brian, June 25, 1996
    Morris, Tom, July 24, 1996
    Singer, Sally, August 6, 1996
    Weinberg, Samantha, August 6, 1996
    Morris, Tom, September 16, 1996
    Carvalho, Jim, September 30, 1996
  - 1997 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    Notice from Academy of Arts and Letters re: death of Alan Ginsberg, April 5, 1997
    Aronowitz, Al, May 1, 1997
    Adolphe, Bruce (to Judy Boals), August 14, 1997
    "Santo," October 21, 1997
  - 1998 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    Shepard, Sam (to Magic Theater ), April 29, 1998
    Boals, Judy, July 23, 1998
    Callahan, Michael (to Judy Boals), September 14, 1998
  - undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
    "Freddie and Lara" (first names only)
    McAdams, "Coach"
    Multiple authors (first names only)
  - Joseph Chaikin, 1984-1997 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Barry Daniels, 1984-1989
    - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Uncorrected advance proof (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Articles on Chaikin and Shepard (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Photograph of Chaikin by Ray Maichen, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Clippings, 1983-1998
  This series includes news clippings regarding Shepard and his work. A file of undated clippings also includes photocopied fragments of others' work, annotated by Shepard.
  - Clippings, 1983-1988 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Awards, 1988-1998
  This series includes award certificates, correspondence, presentation programs, and clippings for awards Shepard received from the American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, among other institutions.
  - Awards (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Common Wealth Awards in Dramatic Arts program and press release, 1988
    American Academy of Arts and Sciences Fellow list of members selected, correspondence, and certificate, 1989
    American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters Gold Medal for Drama program, 1992
    Theater Hall of Fame Scroll of Honor presented by Rudolph Giuliani, Mayor of the City of New York certificate, 1995
    Star on the Playwrights Sidewalk at the Lucille Lortel Theater, NYC. Certificate announcing the placement of the Star on the sidewalk, news clipping, 1988
- Interviews, 1980-1997
  This series is comprised of a conversation between Bob Dylan and Shepard, circa mid 1980s to early 1990s. No transcript currently exists for these 3 audiocassettes, but the tapes have been transferred to CD as listening copies. Also included are the typescript and galleys for an interview of Shepard by Paris Review, regarding Shepard's writing process, 1997, and an interview with Shepard on National Public Radio's "Fresh Air", August 1996.
  - Conversation between Shepard and Bob Dylan, taped by Shepard. Three sixty-minute Tapes marked "Bob 1"—"Bob 6." Fourth cassette is partly marked "Bob" but is only unrelated music. The three interview tapes have been transferred to CD for listening purposes, circa 1985-1993 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Interview of Shepard on National Public Radio's "Fresh Air," August 1996; Interview of Shepard by Paris Reviewregarding Shepard's writing process. Final typescript and gallery, 1997, August 1996, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Readings, 1991-1994
  This series is comprised of Shepard's notes, correspondence and annotated photocopies of excerpts of his work read at various events. Arranged in chronological order by the event's date.
  - Jack Kerouac film documentary. Correspondence, notes, script material, annotated Kerouac excerpts, sent by Johnny Dark, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - "Malestroms Large and Small: An Evening of Primo Levi," Manhattan Theater Club script and correspondence, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Cowboy Poetry reading which included "Pecos Bill" by Shepard, among 25 poems by others. Performing Group later known as "Green River Ropin' and Recitin' Preservation Society." Correspondence and photocopies of poems, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Published compilations, 1984-1993
  Cover art proposals and galleys for compilations of Shepard's work published by Vintage and Bantam comprise this series.
  - "Y" of New York City (Unterberg Poetry Center on 92nd Street and Lexington Avenue, New York City) includes guest pass, letter regarding travel arrangements, and Shepard's annotated readings (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Galleys for Vintage publication of States of Shock, Far North,and Silent Tongue (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Cover art proposals for trade publications of plays: States of Shock, Far North, and Silent Tongue (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Works by Others, 1984-1998
  Arranged by genre (articles, books, sound recordings, screenplays, short stories and teleplays), most of the works in this series are based on or inspired by Shepard's works. Authors mailed the works to Shepard for his comments, and many items include typescripts annotated by Shepard and correspondence.
  - Articles, 1990-1991, undated
    - Schvey, Henry I. "The Master and His Double: Eugene O'Neil and Sam Shepard" Journal of Dramatic Theory and Criticism, pgs. 49-60 (photocopy), Spring 1991 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Schvey, Henry. "A Worm in the Wood: The Father-Son Relationship in the Plays of Sam Shepard," typescript, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Sparr, Landy; Erstling, Susan; Boehnlein, James. "Sam Shepard and the Dysfunctional American Family: Therapeutic Perspectives," American Journal of Psychotherapy, Vol. XLIV, No.4 (photocopy), October 1990 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Books, 1988, 1990
    - Beckett, Samuel. Stirring Still. Illus. By Louise le Brocquy. Blue Moon Books: New York, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Weber, Bruce. Photocopy of proposed book of photographs of Shepard to raise funds for Film Forum Theater, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Audiocassettes, 1984
    - Lou Reed "New Sensations" RCA 1984; "The Moray Eels Eat at the Holy Modal Rounders" Elektra Records; NightVoices. "Intimacy / Insomnia" (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Screenplays, 1989-1996
    - Beresford, Bruce. "Curse of the Starving Class," 3rd draft, typescript, May 5, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Beresford, Bruce. "Curse of the Starving Class," 4th draft, typescript, July 1, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Cocks, Jay. "Brownsville Girl," 8 page movie treatment, November 1996 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Foote, Horton. "Lily Dale," typescript, November 1995 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Foote, Horton. "Lily Dale," Plano Production. Includes: production notes, one-line schedules, and typescript, December 1995 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Hicks, James. "Defenseless," annotated shooting script and schedule. Film featured Shepard, Barbara Hershey, and Mary Beth Hurt. Directed by Martin Campbell, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Johnson, Randi. "Thin Skin," 1st draft, 19 page typescript, January 12, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Johnson, Randi. "Thin Skin," 2nd draft, 18 page typescript, January 22, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Jones, Tommy Lee and Allen. J.T. "The Good Old Boys."6th draft typescript with location map, wardrobe sketch for Hewey, and shooting schedule, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Ketron, Larry. "The Only Thrill," heavily annotated typescript, location information, and shooting schedule. The film featured Shepard and Diane Keaton, October 1996 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Scholz, John. "When the World Was Green." Revised draft typescript, July 20, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Warchus, Matthew and Nicholls, David. "Simpatico." First draft typescript and correspondence, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Wenders, Wim and Dommartin, Solveig, story. Almereyda, Michael, screenplay. "Until the End of the World, "typescript, with letter from Wenders, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Short Stories, undated
    - Williams, Tennessee. "The Man in the Overstuffed Chair," photocopy from published source (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Teleplays
    - Jacoby, Oren. "America's Playwrights: The Fugitive Kind," treatment for 20 minute television documentary for the American Theater Project. Draft typescript, October 10, no year (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - McMurtry, Larry and Ossana, Diana. "Streets of Laredo." Photocopy of October 1, 1994 re-write. Shepard played the role of Pea Eye Parker (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Framed Posters
  Includes 4 posters that were removed from the collection and framed for exhibit. Additional unframed posters can be found listed within the collection.
  - 28" x 39" framed poster for True Westproduction presented by the Nouvelle Compagnie Theatrale, in French (black background with white lettering)
  - 24 1/2" x 34" framed poster for True West, L'ouest, Le vraipresented by Theatre National, in French (black background with white, red and blue lettering)
  - 20 1/2" x 28" framed poster for the Turkish production of True West, Vahsi Bati (white background with brown hat and red tie)
  - 13 1/2" x 19 1/2" framed poster from the Brazilian production of Fool for Love, Louco de Amor,in Portuguese (black and white photo of woman holding man's leg)
- Oversize Items, 1997, undated
  - Sad Lament of Pecos Bill on the Eve of Killing His Wife. Manuscript musical score by Loren Toolajian, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Restricted letters from Shepard's son, Jesse (Box 27)